David Garner

Technical Lead

<u>dprgarner@gmail.com</u> · <u>Github</u> · <u>LinkedIn</u>

I'm a full-stack web developer and technical team lead based in London. My primary focus is front-end development with JavaScript and React, but I also have considerable professional experience in back-end development with Node.js, Python, and Django. I place a strong emphasis on quality in all of my code, and consider unit testing and code review to be essential parts of the development process.

Skills

- Front-end: React, Redux, TypeScript, RxJS, Sass, Styled Components, Webpack, Recent ECMAScript Features, Responsive Design, ¡Query
- Back-end: Node.js, Python, Docker, Express, Django, Solr, Elasticsearch
- AWS: CloudFormation, CloudWatch, Fargate, Lambda, CloudFront
- Testing: Mocha, Jest, Selenium, React Testing Library, TDD, BDD, pytest
- Source control and CI/CD: Git, Jenkins, TeamCity, Gitlab CI, Subversion
- Command line tools: Vim, Bash, common CLI utilities (sed, grep, make, etc.)
- Process management: Scrum, Kanban, Jira, Trello

Employment History

April 2020 - October 2021: QMetric, London, UK

Senior Front-end Lead, then Technical Lead (from November 2020)

I took ownership of the JavaScript codebases within a home insurance platform.

- I maintained and extended a customer-facing app and a backoffice app for purchasing and modifying home insurance policies, with front-ends and backends-for-frontends implemented in React, Express, TypeScript, and RxJS.
- I provided technical leadership, architecture design, and support on a wide range of parallel projects and initiatives, including the front-end rebuilds of the insurance risk form, the quote landing page, and the payments page, as well as the introduction of user-behaviour-tracking analytics and A/B testing.
- I worked with business analysts and delivery managers to break down high-level business requirements into self-contained user stories for development.
- I participated in large-scale architecture discussions with the other tech leads and tech principals to plan the evolution of our cloud-native, event-driven, microservice-architectured insurance platform, implemented primarily in Java with Domain Driven Design.
- I conducted interviews for candidate front-end developers, as well as setting and marking takehome assessments.
- I organised and conducted onboardings, team training meetings, and technical design discussions within a fully-remote team.
- I initiated and assisted with multiple tech-debt initiatives, including the migration of the codebase away from RxJS, the Docker containerisation of the legacy services, and the introduction of browser-side error monitoring and reporting.
- I designed, prototyped, and initiated the implementation of a Microfrontend architecture across our front-end codebase to support multiple teams developing the same application in parallel.

August 2015 - March 2020: Mintel, London, UK

Software Developer, then Engineering Lead (from March 2019)

I gained a wide range of experience with legacy and new codebases primarily using React, Redux, Django, Solr, and Elasticsearch. I worked on multiple projects, including:

- Apps for aggregating and presenting direct marketing data and consumer survey data into tables, charts, and dashboards;
- Apps for searching, reading, and generating presentations from long-form market research articles;
- Internal tools for browser-based Selenium testing, visual regressions testing, and internal front-end libraries for implementing cross-company stylistic consistency.

As the Technical Lead for a search app:

- I held responsibility for technical direction, tech-debt prioritisation, and code quality standards;
- I worked with Product Development and Project Leads to translate the business and technical requirements for new features into Jira issues for implementation by the developers in London, Chicago, and Shanghai;
- I joined remote and in-person interview panels for potential interns, graduate developers, and senior front-end developers.

In addition to my main project work:

- I designed and reviewed component APIs for the front-end component libraries, emphasising backwards-compatibility and extensibility;
- I helped found the "Front-End Chapter", a cross US-UK team group dedicated to sharing knowledge and best practices in front-end development;
- I gave talks on Visual Regressions testing, TypeScript, Styled Components, and design patterns in React:
- I held a half-day introductory workshop on React and our internal UI Components library;
- I ran a lunchtime "Coding Club" teaching front-end frameworks and TDD;
- I organised and participated in internal coding competitions on competitive game-playing Als and image classification with neural networks.

Education

2011–15: Queen Mary University of London, London, UK

Degree: Doctor of Philosophy (PhD) in Theoretical Physics (String Theory)

As a graduate student, I authored <u>multiple papers</u> published in peer-reviewed academic journals, gave talks at multiple academic institutions, and taught Physics undergraduates.

2007–11: University of Cambridge (Christ's College), Cambridge, UK

Degree: BA with MMath, Mathematical Tripos, First Class/Honours Pass

Interests

Coding

I've contributed to various open source JavaScript projects, attended conferences and meetups on TypeScript, React, and GraphQL, and experimented in personal projects with Svelte, GraphQL, Apollo, NumPy, and TensorFlow.

Other

Board games, heavy metal, folk, sci-fi, fantasy, festivals, travelling, running, craft beer